Please, I'm Jack Callahan, Fox News.
President Trump, speaking with reporters just a few moments ago
at his golf resort in New Jersey,
standing by his earlier stern words
that if North Korea takes any military action
against U.S. or our allies.
I hope that they are going to fully understand
the gravity of what I said.
And what I said is what I mean.
President had tweeted this morning
that military options are locked and loaded.
The president's saying if North Korean leader Kim Jong-un
does anything with respect to Guam or any U.S. ally,
he, quote, will regret it.
North Korea responding to the president's earlier tweet
Pyongyang through a Korean news agency
calling the U.S. a shameless gangster state
and warning preventative war is not an option
that's limited just to the United States.
But behind the rhetoric reported clandestine
diplomatic efforts.
Even though you have the president
and the North Koreans going back and forth
with this rhetoric over the last few days,
there is a back channel discussion
between a senior U.S. diplomat
and a North Korean counterpart.
This is according to the Associated Press
that also reports that those two are discussing
the three Americans who are still imprisoned
in North Korea along with some other issues.
The State Department refuses to comment on this report.
Fox's Rich Edson at the Pentagon,
Russia's foreign minister Sergei Lavrov
estimating the risk of a military conflict
between the U.S. and North Korea
is very high and says that Moscow is deeply concerned.
Southern New Hampshire parts of the Exeter Hospital
evacuated midday by an odor.
17 staff members treated after feeling dizzy and nauseous.
No indication that this was life-threatening in any way.
Many of them have gone home already
and some have been transferred to other hospitals
only because we have shut down our emergency services
at this point.
Dr. Neil Meehan says hazmat crews
are investigating none of the patients
at the hospital was affected.
Fox News, fair and balanced.
For every gun owner, pulling the trigger
and lawful self-defense is the absolute last resort.
None of us want to do it, but what if you have to?
Have you considered the serious financial
and legal consequences that could come
from just doing what you had to do to save your life
or the life of a loved one?
I'm Dana Lash with ENRA.
I carry my firearm every day,
but the truth is right behind your firearm,
your second most important self-defense protection
is a rock-solid carry policy.
That's why I believe in NRA Carry Guard.
It's the most comprehensive coverage
and training for those who carry,
developed by the only brand gun owners can trust
to have their backs, no matter what.
NRA Carry Guard members can choose
up to a million dollars in insurance-backed protection,
plus 24-7 access to a first-response crisis management team,
an online video library, and much more.
Learn more and sign up today at NRAcarry.com
or call 1-866-NRA1234
to become an NRA Carry Guard member right now.
Former disc jockey David Mueller
has rested his case against pop star Taylor Swift
in a Denver courtroom,
suing for defamation over Swift's claim
that he groped her before a concert four years ago.
Swift's security guard on the stand today...
Greg Dent testified he saw the DJ
she accuses of groping her
reach under the singer's skirt
during a 2013 pre-concert meet-and-greet photo session.
The singer testified yesterday
saying David Mueller, quote,
stayed attached to my bare cheek as I lurched away from him.
Swift called it a despicable and horrifying
and shocking encounter.
Mueller claims he touched her rib.
He was fired after Swift told his supervisor.
Fox's Michelle Polino, Taylor Swift,
is countersuing charging sexual assault,
still hoping for health care reform,
the conservative Freedom Caucus is planning an end-run
to try and get a vote on to repeal Obamacare
by using a congressional discharge petition
to bypass congressional leadership.
Freedom Caucus member Jim Jordan of Ohio
telling Fox News...
I just spent the last 10 days
crisscrossing the fourth district of Ohio
and people back there said,
act like you did when you ran for the job.
Make sure you guys do what you told us
you were going to do and keep your promise.
This is a way to do that.
Dallas Cowboys running back,
Ezekiel Elliott will appeal
a six-game suspension for domestic violence
handed down by the NFL today.
The league says following a year-long investigation
it finds persuasive evidence
that Elliott had a physical confrontation
with his girlfriend last summer in Columbus, Ohio.
Elliott's representative calls the NFL's findings
inaccurate, full of erroneous conclusions.
Police in Columbus had decided against pressing charges.
Witnesses and police are reporting gunshots
and screams in at least two areas of Kenya
where residents support opposition presidential
candidate Ralia Odinga.
The unrest breaking out after Kenya's election commission
announcing that President Uhuru Kenyatta
had won a second term defeating Odinga.
Dow Jones industrial average,
rebounding up 14 on Jack Hallowhand.
Fox News Radio.
Here is the latest in local news from Fox News Radio.
A drug task force in Washington County
is charging a St. George man with distributing drugs.
Police arrested David Bennett Wednesday
for allegedly selling meth to a confidential informant.
Bennett is charged with two counts of drug distribution.
He will have his first court hearing on Monday.
Police in St. George say a teenager reported missing
earlier this week has been found safe.
They've been searching for 13-year-old Jenna Ann Bound
since Tuesday. She was found around 6.30 last night.
Police did not release details about where she was found
or why she had gone missing.
It wasn't a good time to go through the gorge last night.
Motorists were delayed as two separate collisions
including a fatal motorcycle crash,
reduced traffic to a single lane,
first crash about 6 p.m. involving a motorcyclist
who crashed along Southbound I-15 near Milepost 15
according to the Arizona DPS.
A motorcycle rider pronounced dead at the scene.
The right lane completely blocked off traffic
through the area backed up for several miles.
A second collision occurred at the same time
about 6 miles south of the motorcycle crash.
Weather for the area partly cloudy in 77 today.
For Fox News Radio, I'm Carl Amar.
This just end.
Putin has ties to Russia.
The exclusive tonight on CNN.
The Kate Dolly Show starts now.
In the councils of government,
we must guard against
the acquisition of unwarranted influence
whether sought or unsought
by the military-industrial complex.
The potential for the disastrous rise
of misplaced power exists
and will persist.
We must never let the weight
of this combination endanger our liberties
or democratic processes.
We should take nothing for granted.
Only an alert and knowledgeable citizen
can compel the proper meshing
of the huge industrial
and military machinery of defense
with our peaceful methods and goals.
So that security and liberty
may prosper together.
What's up? Some great words.
Eisenhower.
Yeah, absolutely.
Welcome to the Kate Dolly Show.
Hope you're doing well.
And of course you can go to
www.katedallyradio.com
Check out the podcast.
And of course you can email me anytime
at www.katedallyradio.com
We are live around the globe, around the country.
And I welcome you to the show.
Of course we have Dave, the investigator.
And it's always fun on a Friday, isn't it?
We're so open and I love that.
And I am so grateful to have
this next guest.
In fact, welcome to the show,
John Kiriakou.
I'm so glad to have you.
Thank you.
You bet.
Thank you so much.
I'm so happy to be with you.
Oh, us as well.
In fact, I thank Dave for getting you on the show
and his hat tip to him.
Because this is going to be so good.
In fact, let me tell the audience
just a little bit about you.
For 14 years you worked as an analyst
and case officer for the CIA,
leading the team that captured
a senior Al Qaeda member.
I can never say this guy's name.
There we go.
And I'm the name murderer, John.
In Pakistan in 2002,
and then in a television interview in 2007,
three years after you had resigned
from the U.S. intelligence agency,
you became the first current
or former member of its publicly
acknowledged the CIA that they used torture
and that its use was official policy
under the administration of Bush.
And so in 2012, Barack Obama
administration filed espionage charges against you.
And those charges were eventually dropped
in October of that year.
And you pled guilty to violating
the Intelligence Identities Protection Act
by confirming the name of the officer
involved in then secret CIA rendition program
that transferred CIA detainees
into secret prison facilities around the world,
sentenced to 30 months, served two years.
You have two books, Doing Time Like a Spy,
How the CIA Taught Me to Survive
and Thrive in Prison.
And also The Reluctant Spy,
Your Secret Life on CIA's War on Terror.
If I missed anything, fill in the blanks,
but your story is so compelling.
And as you were writing these books,
was it difficult to kind of know what to say?
Did you have just been in prison
for this under the Barack Obama regime?
Were you a little nervous?
Yes and no.
Yes, in that when I was writing my first book
I was going completely by the book
and every time I would complete a draft
I would send it to the CIA's
Publications Review Board for clearance
and they would either black things out
and send them back or they would send me a letter
saying it looked good.
I did this 11 times, if you can imagine.
I sent 11 separate drafts and in the end
they ended up redacting about 90 pages.
So what would have been a 310 page book
ended up being a 220 page book.
What I didn't know was that every time
I was sending in a new draft
they were filing a crimes report,
it's called, against me with the FBI
saying that I was violating the law
by putting this stuff on paper.
That's not the way it's supposed to work.
The way it's supposed to work is
when they object to something,
I delete it from my computer
negotiate different language with them. Instead, they set out to target me pretty early on in
the book process. You make an important point too, Kate. This all went down during the Obama
administration. Barack Obama, and I'm going to go on record here. I was a third generation
Democrat, and I left the Democratic Party over this because Barack Obama was the enemy
of transparency. Barack Obama liked to tell people that his was the most transparent administration
ever. That's a lie. He was never transparent. There is so much that was done by the CIA and
the rest of the intelligence community in the name of the American people that has
been covered up or papered over that we have a right to know about and a right to
talk about. All of that was covered up by Barack Obama. I decided that I had taken the
CIA's best shot and I survived it. I was going to tell my story. I came out. I wrote doing
time like a spy while I was in prison. I edited it and sent it to the publisher when
I got home from prison. Sky Horse Publishing came to me and said that they wanted me to
write a book with Joe Hickman, a former Guantanamo guard and also a whistleblower, about Abu Zubaydah.
Crazy as it sounds, here we are 15 years plus after the capture of Abu Zubaydah and nobody
had written the definitive book about him. We decided that we would do it. I was the
one who captured him. Joe was the one who guarded him at Guantanamo. We both know
the man personally. We know what kind of person he is. He's very complicated.
He's a bad guy. I think that his defense team is wrong in that they say that he was just
this poor guy. He's the wrong guy. Look what we've done to him. This is terrible. That's
not true. At the same time, he's not the monster that the CIA wants people to believe
that he was. So we thought, well, we'll write this book and put our own thoughts out
there and see what happens. It's been far more controversial than I thought it
would be. People from both the CIA and the FBI have lined up to condemn this report and
actually they've been successful in getting two reviews killed. One was in The Daily Beast,
which is no big deal. But Newsweek had promised us the cover of Newsweek and a 3,000 word
excerpt that was supposed to have appeared three weeks ago. And that just kind of evaporated.
Wow. Is that the Convenient Terrorist? The book? That is the Convenient Terrorist, correct. Very good book. I just
finished reading it yesterday. You've written more than the two books I mentioned, by the way. I just
want to say those were two of your later, you know, your latest, but that one too. Excellent.
It's amazing how it describes the torture techniques used by the CIA and their professional
psychologists versus the FBI's version of interrogation and the conflict between the FBI and the CIA.
And you say they're often just with a wink and a nod sent off to another third world country
present or yes, yes. All the time. What will happen is if I'm in Pakistan, right, and I'm the CIA
counterterrorism chief in Pakistan, and I catch you and you are, let's say, your Egyptian.
If you're an Egyptian in Pakistan and you have no passport and no plausible explanation for what in the world
you are doing there, and I just caught you along the border with Afghanistan, you're going to go to
Guantanamo. I don't care what your excuse is. And what was funny is they had all been trained to tell
the same story. It was almost comical after a while. They all told exactly the same story.
And that story was that they wanted to study Arabic and so they flew to Karachi, never minding the fact that
nobody speaks Arabic in Pakistan. They flew to Karachi and when they arrived they wanted to drive to the
Grand Mosque to give their thanks to Allah for delivering them safely. Well, there is no Grand Mosque
in Karachi. The Grand Mosque is in Islamabad. And when they were in the taxi they accidentally
dropped their passport. And so they got off at the Grand Mosque to pray rather they realized that they
didn't have their passport. So they made their way to an Arabic coffee shop and they met somebody at
the coffee shop who told them, come and stay at this house. We have a lot of Arabs at this house
and we'll get you your passport back and then you can study Arabic and then go home. Well,
they ended up going to an al-Qaeda safe house. They had no idea of course that it was an al-Qaeda
safe house and then the Americans broke down the door and grabbed everybody. And I told this one guy
that we caught, Abu Jaffer al-Iraqi. He was the head of the Durumta training camp in Afghanistan.
And he didn't know that I knew who he was. I said to him, you know how many times I've heard that
story, since I've been in Pakistan, 25 times. You know, I used to respect you guys because
your operational security was so good. This is ridiculous. This is an insult to me.
At least come up with a story that's somewhat believable. You came here to learn how to speak Arabic.
First of all, you're an Arab. You speak Arabic already. They don't even speak Arabic in this country.
No matter what you got.
Gosh, I can't even imagine.
They kind of smiled and nodded and he's like, all right, you got me.
Wow. You know, the book, when you describe the torture that they're under and how we sort of wink
and nod and everything kind of goes just with the wink and the nod, how do you feel about torture?
How do you feel about torture? You've been with the CIA, obviously. What are your thoughts?
You know, I was always, I always felt very, very strongly about the rule of law.
I felt strongly about American exceptionalism, that we're the good guys.
And whether we like it or not, whether we're angry or not, we have to play by the rules,
even if our enemies are not playing by the rules.
Right.
And so I was always opposed to torture, not even, you know, for bleeding heart reasons,
but for rule of law reasons.
Right. Right.
Torture's illegal and reasonable people can agree to disagree on whether or not some of these techniques
that I outlined in the book were torture, but the law says that they're torture.
And if you want to do these techniques, as I say, reasonable people can agree to disagree,
then you have to change the law.
You can't just do it and say, oh, well, it's not torture.
Well, it is, and it's already been decided over the decades, and we can get into that.
Right.
But I was always opposed to this idea of sending people to third countries.
I was saying, if I catch you and you're Egyptian, what you're talking about is then,
I secretly send you to another country, like maybe I send you to Algeria or Jordan or Morocco,
and I tell the intelligence service there, okay, we're sending you this Egyptian wink, wink,
but don't torture him now.
We think he's a really bad terrorist, but remember, you can't torture him.
Just send us a memo and tell us everything he says.
Well, those countries, I mean, all they do is torture.
And so they're going to torture you mercilessly.
You're going to confess to everything.
They're going to write it up as a memo and send it to the CIA,
and they're going to say, well, he gave us all of this information,
but we didn't torture him, we promise.
But some people say, John, how else are we going to get all these secrets
and save millions of lives?
Because you know that's the argument.
What do you say to that?
That's the argument, and it's a red herring.
As we say in the book, and believe me, it's a kick in the gut for me
to have to compliment the FBI.
I hate the FBI, but if there's one thing that the FBI is really good at,
it's interrogation.
And what the FBI does is they establish a rapport or a relationship with a prisoner,
and sometimes it takes weeks and sometimes it takes months,
but after a while, that prisoner is going to open up to his FBI interrogator,
and he's going to give him the intelligence.
So the torture is unnecessary.
You don't need to go that far and violate humanity.
And the media has done a real disservice to the American people,
especially the show 24, which introduced into the popular culture
this notion of the ticking time bomb scenario.
The ticking time bomb scenario is that there's a bomb getting ready to go off
in some American city someplace,
and you have the terrorist who knows about the bomb,
and the only way to get the information is to torture him
so you can defuse the bomb just before it goes off.
Well, that's fantasy.
That's only in the movies and in TV, besides the fact that that never happens
and has never happened in history.
Even if you do torture him, and even if he does give you information,
you then have to turn that information over to a team of analysts.
Right.
Who's going to take weeks or months to work through it
to see what's true and what's not true.
Oh, that's such a great point.
And by then, Chicago's turned to dust.
So the ticking time bomb scenario just doesn't work.
I'm so glad you brought that up.
I'm so glad.
And you're right, and the clock ticks the whole show.
We'll be right back.
Stay with us.
Kate Dally Show.
More with John Kiriakou.
What a fantastic guest this is.
Do not miss a second.
We'll be right back in a couple of minutes.
We'll be right back.
you doing here today Carl? Well I came in here to buy silver and gold because I
heard you were the best guy to buy it from. Well you got that right. I always
figured you for being smart. Well you know I am a smart guy and I tell you
what the future is too uncertain not to invest in silver and gold right now. How
can you trust the dollar and where it's going? Yeah it's actually going down.
See the experts for gold and silver, Greg and Melody at the Goldor store
7 North Main downtown goldorstore.com. If you have a car you need to
listen. This is Kate Dahle and I need you to go get your oil changed at Slick
Willys right now. Trust me they're amazing. At Slick Willys they know there's
millions of places you can get your oil changed so they're completely over the
top with customer service. Customer service? What? You get a bottle of water
and the news with every service and it's fast enough you can just stay
right in your car. They're honest extremely detailed and they'll never
sell you stuff you don't need. Really? I'm so impressed with them. Slick
Willys. My name is Mary Jo and 40 years ago I suffered a neck injury that
changed my life. During those past 40 years I have had pain almost constantly.
I couldn't play with my grandchildren. Holding a baby was was hard on me and
that's not how I want to live. And then it was suggested to me that I go
to see Dr. Brent Norda of Balanced Healthcare. He has been able to
change my life and here I am a year and a half later and I am able to play with
my grandchildren. I'm able to enjoy time with my family again because I'm not in
pain and I can join in a lot of fun. I am back to my old self and have my life
again. If you're suffering and have tried different options but they aren't
working for you I'd like to suggest that you try Dr. Brent Norda at Balanced
Healthcare. You can find them at BalancedHealthStGeorge.com. I don't
want to say Dr. Norda is a miracle worker but he has been for me. I don't get it.
Why aren't people buying our tennis balls? Yeah, me. I mean they're fuzzy, they're
yellow, they're bouncy. I will no doubt about it. We have the bounciest balls
in the business. If people knew how bouncy our balls are. They would be
bouncing on tennis courts from North Carolina to California. Instead they
buy our competitors clearly inferior balls. Yes, smack their balls a few
hundred times and the fuzz balls right off. And soon their balls are
totally bald and barely bouncy at all. What do we need to do to get
people to try our tennis balls? We gotta get the word out. Word out, word out.
Hey, maybe we should advertise. That costs money and we don't have much
money. So yeah, I don't want to advertise until we have more money. Which
we'll get when we sell more balls and make some profits. So we don't need
to advertise, we just need to wait. For what? For profits. You're
absolutely right. Sometimes. I'm so brilliant I actually scare myself.
Yeah, gave me goosebumps. Can I see one? Hold up. While you're waiting,
your competitors aren't. They know something you don't know. It's
called advertising and it works. So get on the ball. This message
brought to you by this station, the Radio Advertising Bureau and
produced by the famous Radio Ranch. Hello, this is Dr. Brent Norder
from Balanced Health Care with a little bit more about Stukkey
Family Pharmacy. Last January, we wanted to do a sugar detox in
our clinic. To really do our project well, we wanted everyone to
be able to measure their blood sugar on a daily basis and to
keep a log of how they were doing. Stukkey Family Pharmacy
stepped up and offered us all the supplies we needed at a
much better price than we could have gotten anywhere else. And
they did that for all their clients. My wife loves them with all
of her individual and specific needs. They're an amazing
partner. I went in there once looking for a certain B12 shot
that didn't have cyanide in it. Stukkey immediately steered
me saying, hey, the shots are good and they can be convenient,
but the sublingual B12, the methylcobalamine is way
better and way healthier. And really it's those personal
touches that makes the difference with Stukkey Family
Pharmacy. So do yourself a favor and get over to Stukkey Family
Pharmacy, again located in Washington behind Red Robin 627
8848 Stukkey Family Pharmacy.
Talk lines are open now. Call 888-673-1450. This is the
Kate Dally show.
Oh man, love that song. Anyway, welcome back to the Kate Dally
show. Glad you're joining us. I've got investigator Dave with
me because it's Friday, always an amazing Friday. We have an
amazing guest, John Kiriakou, 14 years with the CIA. Welcome to
the show. How are you?
Thank you very well. Thank you.
Absolutely. In fact, I want to I want to keep talking about
what our last subject was. And if people are just joining
us, I know they come in and out of the show, we were talking
about torture and your feelings as a as an ex CIA guy on the
matter, and that there has to be a level of humanity in which
we operate. If we want to be the good guy, we have to at
least have a playing field of humanity here in those
techniques. But talk about torture laws.
Well, we've got very specific and very clear laws in the
United States that ban torture. It started in 1946 with the
Federal Torture Act. This is in the immediate aftermath of the
Second World War. And so we passed this law that prohibited
literally all of the techniques that the CIA ended up using
against al-Qaeda prisoners in the in the last decade. I would
remind people to why I shouldn't even say remind because
most Americans don't even know this. But in 1946, we
executed Japanese soldiers who had waterboarded American
prisoners of war. So so waterboarding was an executable
offense in 1946. In 1968, January 17, 1968, the Washington
Post ran a front page photograph of an American soldier
waterboarding in North Vietnamese prisoner. On the day that
that photo ran, the Secretary of Defense at the time, Robert
McNamara ordered an investigation that soldier was
arrested. He was charged with torture, convicted and
sentenced to 20 years in a military prison. So the law
never changed, right? We changed. In addition to this 1946
Federal Torture Act, we are both the signatories and the
primary drafters of the United Nations conventions against
torture, which has the force of law in the United States as
international law that we voted yes on. So these these laws are
very clear. And the law didn't change. We changed. And we
believed that desperate times called for desperate measures
in the aftermath of 9 11. I would say that we lost a part of
our humanity when we made that decision to do the same kind of
things that so many of our enemies do. Now these
techniques, which we go through in the book in great
detail, these are techniques that over the years have been
used by the Chinese communists by the Vietnamese communists by
the Belgians in the Congo, you know, the Nazis, these are things
that the bad guys have done over all these years. And we
decided in 2001 and early 2002, that right or wrong, we were
going to do the same things. We did and completely
justified. Can you talk about you talked about in your
book and how we justified it and made it legal? Well, we
did and how we circumvent protected the CIA. Can you dress
up for a little bit? Yeah, you know, one of the things that the
CIA leadership insisted on at the very beginning was that the
Justice Department promised that there would never be any
prosecutions of any CIA officers who were carrying out these
torture techniques. And certainly, nobody has ever
been arrested or charged or even investigated for a crime.
So everybody sort of knew instinctively that these things
were illegal. And I'll tell you why I've come to that
conclusion. This was a long process to get these techniques
approved. It has to go first to the Justice Department. They
make changes and send it back to the CIA. Then it goes to the
Office of Legal Counsel at the Justice Department and then
they make their changes. And then it goes to the attorneys
at the National Security Council, then it goes to the
Director of the National Security Council. And then finally it
goes to the President for signature. Well, I happened to
be briefing Director George Tenet in his morning staff
meeting, which I did every single morning, the day that we
got the signed memo back from the President. And three times
in that meeting, Tenet said, like almost to himself, I can't
believe the President signed that memo. I can't believe the
President signed that memo. And it made me realize that we
had just asked for permission to do everything. We just asked for
the kitchen sink. Thinking that somewhere along the way, the
lawyers were going to say no. And the lawyers are going to take
some of these techniques out. And nobody did. And then the
President signed it. And we had carte blanche to do anything we
wanted.
And you don't have a people opposing it. American people
want to oppose it. So give it the green light. Why not?
Exactly. Because we were traumatized. I mean, 3000
Americans were killed that day, right? Or whatever it was 2000
Americans, whatever it was, I was almost 3000 my mind now 3000.
Yeah. Yeah, 3000 people. And so this was the greatest
intelligence failure in American history. So people, you know, in
the CIA, at the Pentagon, we wanted revenge. And we wanted,
well, to use Dick Cheney's terms, we wanted the gloves to
come off.
You know, talking about 9 11 talk to me about the knowing of
the Iraq war, the carefully laid plans way before. I've
talked about the PNAC on the show quite often. How many of our
politicians right now were involved in the writing of that
PNAC that came out a year before
11 but tell me a little bit about our carefully laid plans to go in there yeah
you know this is this is so ugly and so controversial it's something that
Americans just don't either don't know about or don't appreciate right there's
a kind of a famous story here in Washington that on September the 12th
2001 a group of neo-conservative private citizens you know Washington fixtures
Richard Pearl for example went to see the president and on that day September the
12th they said we have to attack Iraq well I can tell you that the
intelligence and I'm saying this as a CIA insider the intelligence was crystal
clear that Saddam Hussein in Iraq had absolutely nothing to do with September
11th right what what most Americans don't get is that there was nothing Muslim
about Saddam Hussein there's this famous story that he made the minor pilgrimage
the Omrah to Saudi Arabia to Mecca in 1986 and he went with his vice president
is that Ibrahim who was very religious well Saddam Hussein was so not
religious at all that he didn't even know the prayers and so when he went to Mecca
and got down on his hands and knees to prostrate himself is that Ibrahim had to
whisper the prayers to him so Saddam could then repeat them out loud to make it
look like he was religious hmm hmm there was nothing religious about this guy
and Al Qaeda was a very religious organization they hated Saddam Hussein
as much as they hated the United States so the notion that Saddam had
somehow colluded with Al Qaeda was ridiculous but this was the the theory
being pushed by Dick Cheney's office OVP the office of the vice president well
there was a there was an Iraqi national named Ahmed Chalabi Chalabi had been a
CIA cooperator for many years and the CIA determined that Chalabi was a
pathological liar and he was a thief and so the CIA issued something called
a burn notice against him meaning that no CIA's officers allowed to have any
contact with Ahmed Chalabi so what did Chalabi do? Well Chalabi had very very
close contacts in the neocon movement in Washington and so he started passing
his intelligence to the office the vice president and they in turn passed it
to the Pentagon so it was the Pentagon that was issuing these these
intelligence reports saying Saddam's talking to Al Qaeda the Iraqi station
chief in Prague is talking to Al Qaeda there are weapons of mass destruction
and at the CIA we're saying whoa wait a minute we haven't seen any of this
intelligence but here it's being reported in Pentagon channels I wonder
who their source could be not knowing that it was Chalabi and his people
passing it directly to the Pentagon in Washington this was not being
collected in Iraq right or in the field elsewhere what's going on in Washington
it was being created in Washington and so that's why there were multiple sides to
the weapons of mass destruction story there was no CIA information that there
were weapons of mass destruction but the information was in intelligence
community databases because it was being generated by the Pentagon okay
I have a question because you're an insider do these how much cacophony of
information is going on in there you've got the FBI you got CIA you got the
Homeland Security you got the Pentagon you got everybody else and they're all
coming up with different sources and think this is not really monolithic is
it oh heavens no that's a great question it's not in any way monolithic I'm not
exaggerating when I tell you my job when I was executive assistant to the
CIA's deputy director for operations I would get to my desk at 3 30 in the
morning because I had a 7 a.m. briefing with the deputy director and then a 7 30
briefing with the director and so I had to get through at least 10,000 cables
between 3 30 a.m. and 7 a.m. now it was because I had a very deep expertise on
Iraq that I was chosen for this job and I could get through 10,000 cables so
you look at them as quickly as possible and you say this one's nonsense
nonsense this one's plausible nonsense nonsense and then you go through the
plausible ones and then you really have to think about what makes sense and what
doesn't make sense and then you have to look at the sourcing so that's the
only way to to get to the real story and at the same time we had this thing
called the the threat matrix I'm sure that you've you've heard about this
in the press when we were going from like yellow to orange to red
words back then you remember that oh yeah the color threat so we had this
thing called the threat matrix and the threat matrix was originally meant to
be just an inside tool for those of us who were going through these thousands
and thousands of cables to use to determine what threat was real and
what threat was not real well as soon as the president heard that we had
this threat matrix he demanded access to it the problem is that the
intelligence is raw when it goes into the matrix it's not finished
intelligence and it's not been analyzed by anybody so any lunatic who walks in
off the street into the American Embassy in say you know to go to Galba he
says yeah yeah I'm I'm with Al Qaeda and I'm gonna blow up the American
Embassy in you know Cairo mm-hmm we say okay well you also seem to be insane
and he said yeah you know the space aliens told me to do it right you know
the Shah of Iran mm-hmm and you say okay well normally the officer would write
it up and say this is the information the guy gave he's clearly a lunatic he
was confused and he left right well but the information still goes into the
threat matrix and the next thing you know the National Security Council is
saying oh my god there's a threat against the American Embassy in Cairo we have
to go up to condition orange explains it because nobody's really got any
expertise and the people who do have expertise don't have the authority to
hold back the information and so you've got the policymakers literally
leading the intelligence and then that's how you end up with these with these
situations where you know we go to war saying that there are weapons of mass
destruction and there are no weapons of mass destruction right and so knowing
that and knowing the history of the situation at hand how do you feel about
North Korea right now and Guam it it's history repeating itself it's like
this is exactly what happened with Iraq let me draw a parallel mm-hmm I have
always believed very firmly there you let me let me back up I have a degree in
Middle Eastern Studies I studied Islamic theology that was my my focus I speak
Arabic I lived in the Middle East for many years so I like to think I know
what I'm talking about relative to them in the Middle East okay I was a firm
believer that war with Iraq even if there had been weapons of mass
destruction could have been avoided because we did not understand I should say
the White House did not understand Saddam Hussein's mindset and Saddam Hussein
did not understand the White House's mindset it became well I'm gonna use
this term it became a pissing match between Saddam and George W. Bush so
Bush would say you know don't cross this red line right well in Arab
culture that's an invitation to cross the red line you can't bully somebody in
in Arab culture they just to save face they have to stand up to that threat mm-hmm
and same thing when we you know demanded that Saddam accept the United Nations
weapons inspectors well culturally he couldn't accept those weapons inspectors
because it was humiliating for exactly and Saddam really believed that Bush
would eventually back off because Saddam thought that Bush understood that Saddam
was the only one standing up to the Iranians and the Iranians really were
the real enemies wasn't the Iraqis the Iraqis couldn't attack us they had no
weapons they had no delivery systems they had no nuclear program the
Iranians do mm-hmm and the Iranians certainly frightened the other Arabs in
the Gulf but Bush did not understand the Arab mindset and so it was just
constant pushing pushing pushing until finally Saddam said oh my gosh the
Americans aren't going to back off after all I better get out of here and try to
find someplace to hide and the next thing you know we were crossing the
border I remember also sitting in a secure video teleconference one morning
and it was a pretty high level not even pretty it was a very high level video
briefing I was the note taker oh George Tennant and the other
participants were you know the vice president oh can you save John save this
for save this for about two seconds from now save this for about two seconds will
be right back don't go anywhere I want to hear this story
kdallyradio.com don't go anywhere
I just talked to my CPA and I'm pretty angry he told me that I owe the
care penalty of over $2,000 to the IRS on top of my other taxes because I didn't have
a qualified health plan last year, and he tells me that the penalty is going to be even
higher this year.
Luckily, I'm not going to have to deal with that anymore.
I decided to opt out of the whole Affordable Care Act, including the IRS penalties.
How's that possible, you ask?
I just heard about a medical cost sharing organization, and that as a member, I'm
exempt to the ACA individual mandate and the IRS penalties.
I do get to keep my doctor because there are no networks, no HMOs, no PPO's.
I can go wherever I like.
Best of all, the monthly sharing amount for my family is only $449, a month.
All the information you need is at medicalcostshare.com.
If it makes sense, you can even enroll online.
Take some time and read the guidelines and see if it's right for you.
Medicalcostshare.com.
It's not health insurance, it's better.
Mitsubishi bringing backpacks, school supplies, food and clothing donations for a
chance to win a new iPad.
While you're there, check out the Mitsubishi Outlander.
Perfect for carpooling kids with its three-row, seven-passenger seating and 31
miles per gallon highway.
Now you can lease a 2017 Outlander for as low as $239 a month.
So donate backpacks, school supplies, food and clothing at Paters for a chance
to win a new iPad, 1600 Hilton Drive next to Capping World.
STK number M0563, $3,000 to assign the includes first month payment,
36 months, 10,000 miles per year, OAC.
Would you like to have the healthiest kid on the block?
If you're a parent who wants answers to ensuring your child's health,
you'll want to attend a free seminar on Wednesday, August 16th.
The team at Balanced Health Care will feature Dr. Shane Priest,
a father and chiropractor specializing in pregnancy and pediatrics.
Dr. Priest will be sharing ideas for maximizing your children's health
and talking about why it is so important to have a plan in place
in order to avoid the pitfalls that so many children seem to have
problems with.
Dr. Priest will be discussing nutritious meal and snack ideas,
sleep health, protecting your child's growing body and everything in between.
You won't want to miss this free seminar all about your kid's health
on Wednesday evening, August 16th.
Seating is limited so register soon.
For more information go to Balanced Health St. George dot com.
That's Balanced Health St. George dot com.
It's always about the details.
Hi, this is Ryan from St. George Car Wash and Detail Center.
The reason St. George Car Wash has so many loyal customers
is because we pay attention to the details when it comes to detailing a vehicle.
Our staff is trained and has years of experience
in knowing how to expertly care for and painstakingly detail any vehicle.
Cars, trucks, or RVs.
If it's important to you, trust it only to St. George Car Wash
and Detail Center just off the freeway on South Bluff Street.
Welcome back. Kate Dally's show at your service.
I've got Dave Investigated Dave with me.
Always a fun Friday and always just an intriguing Friday, isn't it?
We've got John Kiriakou who joins us.
He's XCIA and has written some tremendous books.
I have to say really good and you need to pick these up.
As far as, man, there's so many.
The first by is one of the last ones that you've written,
My Secret Life and the CIA's War on Terror.
John, you have so much to say.
Gosh, I wish we had like three hours with you today.
I just want you to kind of go over just from the beginning
of that little story you were telling,
because I wanted to get your thoughts on North Korea
and so we went kind of back to you, this Saddam Hussein,
you were drawing a parallel.
Yes, so I was participating in a secure video teleconference
in very early 2000, well, it was the middle of 2002.
And it was, I was the note-taker for George Tenet,
who was the director of the CIA at the time.
And the other participants, all on video screens,
were the vice president and Condi Rice,
who was the national security advisor, Colin Powell.
Donald Rumsfeld was the secretary of defense
and they all had their note-takers.
And one of the NSC participants said,
and I'll never forget it, he said,
as soon as we cross the border into Iraq,
the Iraqi people are going to throw flowers at us.
And I remember George Tenet turning around,
he turned his microphone off, and he turned around
and he said to me, are these people insane?
Oh my gosh.
Yeah.
Yeah, they're insane.
Yeah, they are.
And we're seeing the same thing now with North Korea.
We are not, if we were to enter North Korea,
we would not be greeted as liberators.
Because North Koreans don't know any better.
You know, they are exposed to the same kind of,
well I shouldn't say the same kind of media,
but they're exposed to a kind of media
that prohibits any outside thought or outside information.
And, you know, you think we would have learned
our lesson by now that foreign interventions
are never easy, they're never clean,
they're never cheap, and for whatever reason,
we never seem to have an exit strategy.
And I'm seeing now the same mistakes being made
at this early stage that we were making
in the early stages of the Iraq war.
Yep, but people are falling.
Where we're just not thinking this thing through.
People are falling for it, and I made the observation
publicly that, you know, we marvel at North Koreans
and how they have to worship him
and how they do because they have been brainwashed
and forced to believe, believe, believe their whole lives.
And we over here do it voluntarily,
and we do it because we don't ask questions.
And so, what enemy, what enemy says,
this is where I'm going to hit,
and it's going to be not really you guys,
but the territory that's far away from you guys.
And so, none of this makes sense.
In fact, if he launched, we would kill that missile
in the air anyway.
This is so preposterous and ridiculous,
but Americans won't ask questions.
They're so wrapped up in the emotion
of the insults being going back and forth
as top headline news.
I posted something on Facebook today
that was meant sort of tongue-in-cheek.
It was one of these men on the street interviews
where the reporter was asking random people,
should we attack North Korea?
And they all said yes.
And then he shows them a map and says,
can you tell me where North Korea is?
And three of them pointed at Canada,
two pointed to Finland.
And this is so typical of the United States
where we take these positions,
and we don't have any idea what we're doing
or what we're talking about.
Yep. We're just taught to think a certain way.
That's amazing.
I agree with you completely.
This is an utter lack of information,
and even if we had the information,
it's a lack of analysis.
Yes. Yes.
Oh, my gosh.
I can't stress that enough.
And what do you think will happen?
What do you think will happen in the coming week?
What do you foresee?
I think we're serious.
We're going to say these words,
but I expect that the Chinese will finally
intervene with both sides,
and cooler heads will prevail.
I can't believe that we're looking to the Chinese
for leadership.
But here we are.
Wow.
We live in a bizarro world now.
A false flag.
How do you feel about those words?
You know, it depends, really.
False flags were actually very popular
at the CIA when I was there.
Not on grand scales,
because the bigger the false flag,
the tougher it is to pull it off.
But operationally, false flags were very popular.
They used them all the time.
I'm glad you at least commented on that.
You know, those words are so taboo.
Very good.
They are, you know, because they're loaded.
For example, I don't believe that the new town
massacre was a false flag.
I think it was a massacre.
And it's funny to me that I have so many friends
who believe that everything is a false flag.
And it's like, dude, you know,
I want to tell people,
if you knew the morons,
some of the morons I worked with at the CIA,
you would never use the words false flags again,
because these guys can't find their way to the men's room,
let alone manipulate governments and countries.
Interesting.
What is your take on Russia and the allegations
with Trump and Russia?
Because I don't believe it for a second.
But what do you...
I actually don't believe it for a second either.
I'm a member of a group called
Veteran Intelligence Professionals for Sanity.
We've got about five dozen former CIA,
FBI and NSA, mostly senior officials.
In some cases, you know, the number two
or the number three or number four in some of these agencies.
And we take very in-depth looks
at some of these major issues,
and then we issue memoranda to the president,
which he probably never reads,
but they also get published in places
like Consortium News or The Nation Magazine.
And we wrote one a few days ago
on this Russia collusion thing.
It was written by Bill Benny,
who was the number four at NSA
and is one of the country's leading experts
on internet security.
And we've come to the conclusion
that there is just no evidence of collusion.
There's no evidence that the Russians
hacked into the DNC servers.
The evidence that we do have points to
a whistleblower inside the DNC
who printed the documents off,
gave them to the former British ambassador
to Uzbekistan, Craig Murray.
And Craig delivered them to WikiLeaks.
And Craig has said publicly
that that's exactly what happened.
So I'm just not seeing any collusion.
between the Trump campaign and the Russians.
I just don't think it's there.
I think the Paul Manafort thing was all,
I don't like him, but it was all theater, theater, yeah.
Yeah, it's all theater.
You know, John Stockwell, the CIA agent
that came out in the 80s,
said something that I'll never forget,
and I've regurgitated it a couple times on the show,
that he was always, when he was told to do things,
he always thought that he would get the answer
as to why, and as long as he kept moving up
the food chain, and then when he got
to the top of the food chain,
he was never given answers.
It was all smoke and mirrors.
What are your thoughts on that, being in the CIA?
I think that's absolutely true, absolutely true.
You know, when I got this job as the executive assistant
to the ADDO, the associate deputy director for operations,
I mean, that's a pretty doggone, high level position.
In that, even though I'm the assistant,
I then have access to, I thought, literally everything.
Right.
Because that's the only way
that I can keep him briefed or informed.
Well, there were databases that I had access to
called Compartmented Databases,
and I remember a couple of times like starting
to brief something that I had read
from one of these databases, and he stopped me
because the other associate deputy directors
didn't have access to the information.
And so I would have to give it to him hard copy,
and he said, you know, you can't mention this
in front of anybody else.
Oh my God, these are the top,
top most people in the CIA.
Right.
And they're not cleared for the information.
So it was that that made me understand that,
oh, this went way higher than I had ever thought.
Right.
I mean, it went above the CIA even.
I mean, look at Richard Helms, for example,
the former CIA director,
who went fishing one day,
and then mysteriously died in his canoe
all by himself and fell overboard and drowned.
I mean, how does that happen?
Well, don't you worry about that?
I mean, John Stockwell, I think he's still alive.
Don't you worry about that?
Don't you worry about saying things
that I mean, a lot of people turn up dead,
especially if you know the Clintons
or pass the Clintons in traffic
or brush up against them in a hotel or whatever.
Lots of people around the Clintons die.
Don't you worry about that in this position?
Because whistleblowers are right out there,
you know, in the open.
They are.
Do you worry?
People ask me that all the time,
and to tell you the honest to God's truth,
yeah, I am a little bit worried about it,
but I like to think that if I remain as vocal
and as out there as I possibly can be,
shouting the truth, that people will miss me.
And I like to think that that's what keeps me safe.
Wow.
I have a question.
Sure.
Since you were talking about torture,
are we still doing it?
The wink and the nod.
Oh, that's another good question.
You know, Barack Obama said that we weren't.
I believe him.
I believe everything he says.
Who knows?
It's all secret.
Right.
Because I believe it.
I told an interview with the other day
that when the CIA told the American people
that there was no torture program, that was a lie.
When they said that there were no secret prisons,
that was a lie.
When they said that they were not rendering prisoners
to third countries, that was a lie.
When they say that they had not
hacked into the Senate's computer system,
that was a lie.
So why should we take their word for it now?
I totally agree with you.
With everything else that they've told us has been a lie.
Yep.
I totally agree with you.
I wish people would follow the dots on that.
And how do you feel about the CMUs,
the secret management units,
the communication management units
where people are completely denied
of all their rights if they're a political prisoner?
They're located in, I think, Indiana, Illinois?
I was threatened with placement in a CMU.
When I started writing this block series from prison
that became the book, Doing Time Like a Spy.
So they threatened me with transfer to another prison
and placement in the CMU.
Oh my gosh.
The management unit.
Right.
Communications management unit.
And I decided to use a little bit of bluster.
And I told the warden right to his face.
He stopped me coming out of the cafeteria
at lunch one day to threaten me.
And I said, warden, I have gone nose to nose
with Al Qaeda, with Hezbollah, with the Iranians,
and I'm supposed to be afraid of your prisons?
Please, I said, give me a little bit of credit.
My sentence is short, and I'm gonna go home,
and I'm gonna tell the American people
what happens inside these prisons.
You can't scare me into silence.
Whoa.
You know, I, yeah.
I fear, wow.
I fear that Congress oversees this,
but they don't do anything about it.
We see these things, they'll never, ever go away.
And they're so, it's like a little mini Guantanamo, really,
because they could be put in a hole.
People could be put in a hole.
These are people that really haven't harmed anyone.
This is just mostly a lot of political prisoners.
And so they could be put in a hole, and you wouldn't know.
And they could be stuck down there for 25 years.
There's no accountability, border prisons,
no accountability whatsoever.
Why does that not get out?
Why doesn't that worry Americans
that we have this right here in good old USA?
You are absolutely right.
And in the federal prison system,
they use this technique called diesel therapy.
I was threatened with diesel therapy
and a friendly administrator warned me.
He said, hey, they're talking about
putting you in diesel therapy.
I said, what's that mean?
I had never heard it before.
What it means is, they put you in something
called transit status.
That's that you're being transferred to another prison.
So I would go from,
I was in the federal prison at Laredo, Pennsylvania.
They would send me to the US Penitentiary
in Canaan, Pennsylvania.
And I'm there for three days or three weeks
or three months or whatever.
And then from there, they'd send me to Atlanta
and from Atlanta to Oklahoma City,
which is the National Transportation Hub
and from Oklahoma City to another place
and another and another.
With the idea being, if you are in transit status,
you're not allowed to have access to a phone,
to an email system or to pen and paper.
Zip.
And so people literally have no idea
where you are in the country.
Oh.
And you can't contact anybody.
It's amazing.
And I want, just before we go,
we have about a minute and a half.
I just, down here in these parts
where I'm at, the Bundy situation,
where no shots were ever fired
and the protesters didn't have guns
and you've got a kangaroo court in Las Vegas
where a constitution isn't allowed.
They're not allowed to have a defense.
Are you surprised by this?
What do you see happening there?
No.
I'll tell you, the only thing that surprised me
about the Bundy situation
was that they were acquitted in the end.
I supported them just because,
like I said earlier in the show,
I feel so strongly about rule of law.
And I believe in civil liberties.
I consider myself to be a libertarian.
And I think that the federal government
was just trampling all over their constitutional rights.
Yep.
They still are.
I was real that a jury came to the same conclusion.
Yeah.
Yeah, they were acquitted in Oregon,
but now they're trying to.
They're so afraid of it
that they have the biggest kangaroo court
I think I've ever seen,
the trials and the jokes.
Oh, and this is what the feds will do.
They'll just keep trying them over and over and over again
on trumped-up charges
until they finally get a conviction.
Geez.
It's just so sick.
You know, what are we gonna do as Americans?
I mean, this could affect anyone
for standing up for themselves.
I can't even imagine.
I wanna say one last thing.
I have a couple of...
Yeah, go ahead.
There's a study that came out in 2012 by ProPublica.
That is the investigative journalism website.
And in this study,
they found that the federal government wins
98.2% of its cases.
93.2% of its cases.
When I was at the CIA,
and Saddam Hussein would win 98%
of his presidential election,
we would laugh and we would say that the fix was in.
Well, the feds win 98% of their cases
and we say they're geniuses.
Well, they're not geniuses.
The system is rigged.
Yeah, they're bought and sold.
John Kiriakou, what a pleasure it was
to have you this hour.
I can't say that strongly enough.
We'll have you back.
A reluctant spy, my secret life
in the CIA's war on terror
and many other books, check him out.
Thank you so much.
What a pleasure.
Thank you.
And of course, be faithful, be fearless.
Go to katedallyradio.com for podcasts of the show.
Hello, Washington County. It's Glen Beck.
And if you're selling your home right now,
you may be thinking the market is hot
and all you need to do is hire any agent
and your home is automatically gonna sell.
Let me tell you, that is a huge mistake.
Here's what you need to do.
Rather than just getting a price quote,
I want you to take a close look at the marketing plan
of the agent you're talking to.
That marketing plan has to create demand for your home.
Now I'm gonna save you a lot of time and frustration.
I want you to start with the one group
that has the most innovative marketing in Washington County.
His name is Jeremy Larkin
and the Larkin group of Keller Williams Realty.
Now rather than just rely on balloons
or Craigslist ads week after week,
what Jeremy and his team does
is they spend thousands of marketing dollars
attracting hundreds of buyers
and that generates multiple offers
and they are selling homes faster
and for more money than the average local agent.
They can even give you an instant offer on your home,
immediately creating demand.
Call Jeremy and the Larkin group at 275-1670
or check out his reviews online
at soldinstjorge.com.
That's soldinstjorge.com.
Fox News Radio, FM 93.1 at AM 1450 KZNU St. George.
FM 98.5 in Cedar City, AM 1400 KZZ, Parallon.
Live from New York, the...